[
	{
		"front": "we will return to our project",
		"back": "volveremos a nuestro proyecto"
	},
	{
		"front": "for everything else",
		"back": "para todo lo demás"
	},
	{
		"front": "I saved that earlier",
		"back": "lo guardé antes"
	},
	{
		"front": "it's right here",
		"back": "está justo aquí"
	},
	{
		"front": "we need to allow the user to upload files",
		"back": "necesitamos permitir al usuario cargar archivos"
	},
	{
		"front": "we will need to add some permissions",
		"back": "necesitaremos agregar algunos permisos"
	},
	{
		"front": "and we will have to check this box",
		"back": "y tendremos que marcar esta casilla"
	},
	{
		"front": "and then scroll down and then back up",
		"back": "y luego desplácese hacia abajo y luego hacia arriba"
	},
	{
		"front": "you can repeat the steps",
		"back": "puedes repetir los pasos"
	},
	{
		"front": "you'll want to copy this password",
		"back": "querrás copiar esta contraseña"
	},
	{
		"front": "you will have to regenerate it",
		"back": "tendrás de regenerarlo"
	},
	{
		"front": "make sure you save them because otherwise you will lose them",
		"back": "asegúrate de guardarlos porque de lo contrario los perderás"
	},
	{
		"front": "I am going to use it to paste some text into the input box",
		"back": "voy a usarlo para pegar algo de texto en el cuadro de entrada"
	},
	{
		"front": "just follow exactly what I do and you should be fine",
		"back": "solo sigue exactamente lo que hago y deberías estar bien"
	},
	{
		"front": "we didn't do anything with it",
		"back": "no hicimos nada con él"
	},
	{
		"front": "and I will delete some of these comments",
		"back": "y borraré algunos de estos comentarios"
	},
	{
		"front": "it may be tempting to create",
		"back": "puede ser tentador crear"
	},
	{
		"front": "let's go back",
		"back": "regresemos"
	},
	{
		"front": "I got to this page by browsing",
		"back": "llegué a esta página navegando"
	},
	{
		"front": "so we can move on",
		"back": "así que podemos seguir adelante"
	},
	{
		"front": "something starts to happen",
		"back": "algo comienza a suceder"
	},
	{
		"front": "belw the image",
		"back": "debajo de la imagen"
	},
	{
		"front": "so let's take a look",
		"back": "así que echemos un vistazo"
	},
	{
		"front": "that investment will pay for itself many times over",
		"back": "esa inversión amortizará muchos veces"
	},
	{
		"front": "it would be nice to find out",
		"back": "sería bueno averiguarlo"
	},
	{
		"front": "the next level",
		"back": "el siguiente nivel"
	},
	{
		"front": "each layer of testing",
		"back": "cada capa de prueba"
	},
	{
		"front": "if you have ever seen a documentary",
		"back": "si alguna vez has visto un documental"
	},
	{
		"front": "it's pretty easy to find out",
		"back": "es bastante fácil averiguar"
	},
	{
		"front": "due to the delta",
		"back": "debido al delta"
	},
	{
		"front": "both approaches",
		"back": "ambos enfoques"
	},
	{
		"front": "pr. 1930",
		"back": "meel NOH-vay see-EN-troh TRAYN-tah"
	},
	{
		"front": "in the last century",
		"back": "en el siglo pasado"
	},
	{
		"front": "click on the tab",
		"back": "haga clic en la pestaña"
	},
	{
		"front": "we will not cover in this course",
		"back": "no cubriremos en este curso"
	},
	{
		"front": "take a couple of minutes and",
		"back": "tómate un par de minutos y"
	},
	{
		"front": "a branch called main",
		"back": "una rama llamada main"
	},
	{
		"front": "a couple of things I want to point out",
		"back": "un par de cosas que quiero señalar"
	},
	{
		"front": "we will leave these unset",
		"back": "dejaremos estos sin establecer"
	},
	{
		"front": "work back and forth",
		"back": "trabajar de un lado de otro"
	},
	{
		"front": "the other thing that happens",
		"back": "la otra cosa que sucede"
	},
	{
		"front": "I'm testing a hunch",
		"back": "pruebo una corazonada"
	},
	{
		"front": "testing a hunch",
		"back": "probando una corazonada"
	},
	{
		"front": "app developer",
		"back": "desarrollador de aplicaciones"
	},
	{
		"front": "this is because it is very difficult to distinguish",
		"back": "esto se debe a que es muy difícil distinguir"
	},
	{
		"front": "it is assumed that",
		"back": "se supone que"
	},
	{
		"front": "this concept helps to emphasize",
		"back": "Este concepto ayuda a enfatizar"
	},
	{
		"front": "let's drink to software development",
		"back": "brindemos por el desarrollo de software; [day-sah-ROY-yoh]"
	},
	{
		"front": "it consists of the following parts",
		"back": "es consta de las siguientes partes; [see-g|ee-EN-tays]"
	},
	{
		"front": "so let's take a look at the general process",
		"back": "así que echemos un vistazo el proceso general"
	},
	{
		"front": "continuous delivery",
		"back": "entrega continua"
	},
	{
		"front": "to a large extent",
		"back": "en gran medida"
	},
	{
		"front": "as we see, the binaries will be generated",
		"back": "como vemos, se va a generar los binarios"
	},
	{
		"front": "having built it on our machine",
		"back": "al haberlo construido en nuestra máquina"
	},
	{
		"front": "Go stands out for the small size of its binaries",
		"back": "Go destaca por el pequeño tamaño de sus binarios"
	},
	{
		"front": "since we would be forcing him to install Go",
		"back": "puesto que le estaríamos obligando a instalar Go [gr. present conditional]"
	},
	{
		"front": "but we can't deliver it to the user like this",
		"back": "pero no podemos entregarla así al usuario"
	},
	{
		"front": "let's start with a small application",
		"back": "partamos de una pequeña aplicación"
	},
	{
		"front": "in which they are going to be executed",
		"back": "en el que se vayan a ejecutar [gr. subjunctive present]"
	},
	{
		"front": "we usually run our programs directly from the source code",
		"back": "solemos ejecutar nuestros programas directamente desde el código fuente"
	},
	{
		"front": "common tasks such as counting requests",
		"back": "tareas comunes como el conteo de peticiones"
	},
	{
		"front": "we should see the message",
		"back": "deberíamos ver el mensaje [gr. present conditional]"
	},
	{
		"front": "this time, we should get the correct answer",
		"back": "esta vez, deberíamos recibir la respuesta correcta [gr. present conditional]"
	},
	{
		"front": "as expected, we have an error",
		"back": "como era de esperar, tenemos un error"
	},
	{
		"front": "whenever we returned an error previously",
		"back": "siempre que devolviéramos un error anteriormente [gr. subjunctive imperfect 1]"
	},
	{
		"front": "we will leave these set as they are",
		"back": "dejaremos estos configurados como están"
	},
	{
		"front": "in order to save it",
		"back": "para guardarlo"
	},
	{
		"front": "I will save that later",
		"back": "lo guardaré más tarde"
	},
	{
		"front": "it's right there",
		"back": "esta justo ahí"
	},
	{
		"front": "as dark as it can be",
		"back": "tan oscuro como puede ser"
	},
	{
		"front": "click on the button",
		"back": "haga clic en el botón"
	},
	{
		"front": "click on the left side",
		"back": "haga clic en el lado izquierdo"
	},
	{
		"front": "on the one hand",
		"back": "por un lado"
	},
	{
		"front": "since we consider it an error",
		"back": "puesto que lo consideramos un error"
	},
	{
		"front": "we will return an error",
		"back": "retornaremos un error"
	},
	{
		"front": "by our web layer",
		"back": "por nuestra capa web"
	},
	{
		"front": "including the value",
		"back": "incluyendo el valor"
	},
	{
		"front": "the time that has elapsed",
		"back": "el tiempo que ha transcurrido"
	},
	{
		"front": "the first thing it does is get the current time",
		"back": "lo primero que hace es obtener la hora actual"
	},
	{
		"front": "as soon as you enter",
		"back": "nada más entrar"
	},
	{
		"front": "that is in charge of counting the requests",
		"back": "que se encargue de contar las peticiones"
	},
	{
		"front": "that is in charge of counting the requests",
		"back": "que se encargue de contar las peticiones [en-KAR-gay]"
	},
	{
		"front": "although we could have used any other",
		"back": "aunque podríamos haber utilizado cualquier otro"
	},
	{
		"front": "we access the URL",
		"back": "accedemos a la URL"
	},
	{
		"front": "start the server on port 8080",
		"back": "arranca el servidor en el puerto 8080"
	},
	{
		"front": "in isolation",
		"back": "de manera aislada"
	},
	{
		"front": "will make a request",
		"back": "hará una petition"
	},
	{
		"front": "it will return the list",
		"back": "devolverá la lista"
	},
	{
		"front": "to test it",
		"back": "para probarlo"
	},
	{
		"front": "finally",
		"back": "por último"
	},
	{
		"front": "let's ask",
		"back": "vamos a pedir"
	},
	{
		"front": "I will store in the variable",
		"back": "almacenaré en la variable"
	},
	{
		"front": "he copies text in all at once, he doesn't type it",
		"back": "copia el texto de una sola vez, no lo escribe"
	},
	{
		"front": "by prompt we understand",
		"back": "entendemos por prompt"
	},
	{
		"front": "you can see on the last line",
		"back": "puedes verlo en la última línea"
	},
	{
		"front": "we will read the answer",
		"back": "leeremos la respuesta"
	},
	{
		"front": "the root directory",
		"back": "el directorio raíz"
	},
	{
		"front": "we will return to the subject",
		"back": "volveremos al tema"
	},
	{
		"front": "which is responsible for making the request to the API",
		"back": "que se engarga de hacer la petición a la API"
	},
	{
		"front": "in the following videos",
		"back": "en siguientes vídeos [see-g|ee-EN-tays]"
	},
	{
		"front": "wouldn't it be better to be able to do something like this",
		"back": "no sería mejor ser capaces de hacer algo así"
	},
	{
		"front": "tens, hundreds",
		"back": "decenas, cientos"
	},
	{
		"front": "text box",
		"back": "caja de texto"
	},
	{
		"front": "the mouse",
		"back": "el ratón"
	},
	{
		"front": "via our browser",
		"back": "mediante nuestro navegador"
	},
	{
		"front": "as we have seen",
		"back": "como hemos visto"
	},
	{
		"front": "la variable habrá sido modificada",
		"back": "the variable will have been modified"
	},
	{
		"front": "will be applied to the struct",
		"back": "se aplicarán a la struct"
	},
	{
		"front": "this pointer will point to the memory address of the value",
		"back": "este puntero apuntará a la dirección de memoria del valor"
	},
	{
		"front": "let's store the value 17",
		"back": "vamos a almacenar el valor 17"
	},
	{
		"front": "an integer value",
		"back": "un valor de tipo entero"
	},
	{
		"front": "leaving the code much cleaner",
		"back": "quedando el código mucho más limpio"
	},
	{
		"front": "let's see this in an example",
		"back": "veámoslo con un ejemplo"
	},
	{
		"front": "if there is any error",
		"back": "si hubiera algún error [subjunctive imperfect 1]"
	},
	{
		"front": "each of which modifies a field",
		"back": "cada una de las cuales modifica un campo"
	},
	{
		"front": "a function that receives a pointer",
		"back": "una función que recibe un puntero"
	},
	{
		"front": "which value corresponds to which field",
		"back": "qué valor corresponde a qué campo"
	},
	{
		"front": "if we were to add new fields",
		"back": "si añadiésimos nuevos campos [subjunctive imperfect 2]"
	},
	{
		"front": "its wide range of packages",
		"back": "su amplia gama de paquetes"
	},
	{
		"front": "Go places a strong emphasis on testing",
		"back": "Go pone un fuerte énfasis en las pruebas"
	},
	{
		"front": "digital signatures",
		"back": "firmas digitales"
	},
	{
		"front": "the library provides many useful tools",
		"back": "la librería proporciona muchas herramientas útiles"
	},
	{
		"front": "to a large extent",
		"back": "en gran medida"
	},
	{
		"front": "high performance",
		"back": "alto rendimiento"
	},
	{
		"front": "the library is highly optimized",
		"back": "la librería está altamente optimizada"
	},
	{
		"front": "file management",
		"back": "manejo de archivos"
	},
	{
		"front": "above the current package",
		"back": "por encima del paquete actual"
	},
	{
		"front": "in such a way that",
		"back": "de tal modo que"
	},
	{
		"front": "higher layers of the application",
		"back": "capas más altas de la aplicación"
	},
	{
		"front": "therefore",
		"back": "por tanto"
	},
	{
		"front": "below it",
		"back": "por debajo de él"
	},
	{
		"front": "such as",
		"back": "tales como"
	},
	{
		"front": "deployment code",
		"back": "código despliegue [des-SPLEE-gay]"
	},
	{
		"front": "let's look at it with a small example",
		"back": "veámoslo con un pequeño ejemplo"
	},
	{
		"front": "and finally, I want to highlight the test directory",
		"back": "y por último, quiero destacar el directorio de pruebas"
	},
	{
		"front": "from outside the project",
		"back": "desde fuera del proyecto"
	},
	{
		"front": "pr. cmd",
		"back": "[say ehm-MAY day]"
	},
	{
		"front": "we can find it in the repository",
		"back": "podemos encontrarlo en el repositorio"
	},
	{
		"front": "a set of organizational patterns",
		"back": "un conjunto de patrones de organización"
	},
	{
		"front": "our hierarchy",
		"back": "nuestra jerarquía"
	},
	{
		"front": "which helps us",
		"back": "lo cual nos ayuda"
	},
	{
		"front": "which is a mistake",
		"back": "lo cual es un error"
	},
	{
		"front": "although it seems to make sense",
		"back": "aunque parece tener sentido"
	},
	{
		"front": "for this reason",
		"back": "por ello"
	},
	{
		"front": "in such a way that",
		"back": "de tal forma de"
	},
	{
		"front": "internal scope of the package",
		"back": "ámbito interno del paquete"
	},
	{
		"front": "we will have to expose the functions",
		"back": "tendremos que exponer las funciones"
	},
	{
		"front": "since it is an implementation detail",
		"back": "ya que es un detalle de implementación"
	},
	{
		"front": "we are hiding it on purpose",
		"back": "lo estamos ocultando a propósito"
	},
	{
		"front": "place the files in that directory",
		"back": "colocar los archivos en ese directorio"
	},
	{
		"front": "code coverage",
		"back": "cobertura de código"
	},
	{
		"front": "it's just the beginning",
		"back": "es solo el principio"
	},
	{
		"front": "you will immerse yourself in the code",
		"back": "te sumergirás en el código"
	},
	{
		"front": "provide you with an understanding",
		"back": "brindarte una comprensión"
	},
	{
		"front": "you are going to start",
		"back": "vas a empezar"
	},
	{
		"front": "optimized performance",
		"back": "rendimiento optimizado"
	},
	{
		"front": "new heights",
		"back": "nuevas alturas"
	}
]